# NIKOL PROKOPOVA

## Web Developer

London, UK n.prokopova96@gmail.com 07549151895 GitHub LinkedIn Portfolio

### **SUMMARY**

I am a Front End Developer with an interesting background. I started off studying biotechnology and worked in the field of genetics on a custom DNA sequencing instrument. Due to my exposure to programming I realised it's a much better fit for me despite finding genetics extremely interesting. That is largely due to the way I think and my love for working with computers. I decided to pursue a career in Web Development and I've worked in the field for two years. I am proficient in Vanilla JS and React, as well as HTML and Vanilla CSS + libraries.

#### **SKILLS**

React (Next.js, Gatsby.js), HTML, CSS (FlexBox, CSS Grid), Node.js Styled Components, Git, GitHub, BitBucket, StoryBook, MaterialUI, Jira, Jenkins, RESTful APIs, Nunjucks, jQuery, SCSS, SQL, Contentful CMS, AWS, Email development, Continuous Integration

#### **EXPERIENCE**

AKQA, London - Web Developer

NOV 2022 - PRESENT

Tech stack: React, TypeScript, HTML, SCSS, jQuery, Nunjucks, Contentful CMS, SQL, Git, BitBucket, JIRA, Jenkins, Node.js, SQL, AWS, Continuous Integration, Mailchimp, Email Development

- Worked at a design agency supporting the development of the front end on various projects
- Led the development, support and deployment of the company website
- Led the development of a React <u>project</u> based on this year's creative requirements to create an animated, interactive web-app
- Supported the marketing team to provide timely and stable solutions to urgent requests
- Managed a MySQL database
- Worked in SCRUM
- Worked on the implementation of Google Analytics 4
- Used Git and ButBucket for version control
- Wrote JIRA tickets

#### Codeum Ltd, London - Junior Web Developer

FEB 2022 - NOV 2022

Tech stack: React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, NextJS, StoryBook, MaterialUI

- Worked at a web agency, creating custom React components to construct UI libraries in StoryBook
- Developed Components for a UI library with Storybook and Material UI Implemented code into NextJS projects
- Created reusable React components according to specifications
- Met with the development team to discuss user interface ideas and applications
- Used Git and GitHub for version control
- Used Jira for project management Worked in SCRUM (biweekly sprints)
- Communicated to team members and management

#### DNA Electronics. London - Associate Scientist

SEP 2019 - NOV 2021

Tech skills: Python, Jira, Jenkins, Data analysis and visualisation

- Worked towards the development of a first of its kind medical device utilising Next Generation DNA Sequencing technology at a dynamic inter-disciplinary start-up
- Designed and conducted experiments for biochemical optimisation of semiconductor sequencing technology
- Led work packages that resulted in significant improvements in sequencing performance
- Modified Python scripts to run experimental machinery
- Led issue-tracking meetings and used Jira as platform and was a laboratory leader
- Troubleshot and communicated with cross-functional team members

### Nanyang Technological University, Singapore - Research Assistant

SEP 2017 - JUN 2018

- Molecular cloning, PCR, Bacterial culture, identification and characterisation
- Used advanced software to design gene constructs
- Constructed bacterial plasmids and performed genetic knock-off mutation in E.coli bacteria

#### **EDUCATION**

**University of Surrey, London** - Biotechnology

JUN 2019

First class honours

#### **CERTIFICATES**

FreeCodeCamp Responsive Web design

<u>Codecademy React Course</u>

FreeCodeCamp JavaScript Algorithms

FreeCodeCamp Front End Development Libraries